It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Musashi vs.
무사시 대
Kojirō
코지로이오
Peace has returned to Edotopia.
에도토피아에 평화가 돌아왔다.
The village became lively again,
마을은 다시 활기차졌고,
Zenigatan's wife Akane's stomach became bigger,
제니가탄의 아내 아카네는 배가 커지고,
See you later!
갔다 올게!
See you.
다녀와.
I'll do the cleaning and washing; you can take a rest.
아, 청소, 세탁은 돌아와서 내가 할 테니까 쉬고 있어.
I know you will.
알았어.
I'll go shopping by myself, too.
장도 내가 볼 테니까.
Yeah, great!
그래, 그래!
Hello, my baby!
안녕, 아가야!
He's so prone to worrying.
걱정이 많아.
Jiraiyan still sells toad oils,
지라이얀은 변함없이 두꺼비 기름을 팔고,
(rokko no oishii mizu: delicious water from Rokko; water brand name)
(록코의 맛있는 물: 브랜드 이름)
Would you like delicious toad oil from Rokko?
에, 록코의 맛있는 두꺼비 기름 어떠세요?
I don't need it.
필요 없어요.
Oh, alright.
아, 그래요?
I guess we won't have dinner again today.
오늘도 저녁은 없겠네.
Ushiwaka and Benkei teach swordsmanship to the swordsmen of Edo Castle,
우시와카, 벤케이는 에도 성의 무사에게 검술을 가르치며,
Louder!
목소리를 키워라!
Yessir!
예!
Ieyasu has a conversation with Saigo who came to met him,
이에야스는 그를 찾아온 사이고와 간담을.
Baiken brothers in Hokkaido are sweating for their field works,
홋카이도의 바이켄 형제는 밭일에 땀을 흘리고,
and...
그리고...
Musashi and others are now in Miyako Palace.
무사시하고 나머지라 하면 미야코 팔레스에 와 있었다.
Musashi! Can't you eat with manners?
무사시, 좀만 더 예의바르게 못 먹겠냐!
Gyoza-dasu? Where, where? Where? Where, where, where?
교자이오? 어? 어디이오? 어디? 어디어디어디?
Senhime looks happy.
센히메 님, 행복해 보여.
You're right-dasu!
그렇소!
Those two look good together.
저 둘, 잘 어울려.
We look good together, too-dasu!
우리도 잘 어울리오!
Mr. Musashi...
저런, 무사시 씨도 참.
They're so simple-minded...
천진한 놈들이야...
Oh, no.
저런.
Delicious-dasu.
맛있소.
Musashi! How dare you take my meatball!?
무사시! 내 고기 완자를 잘도!
Anyway, isn't it great-dasu?
그래도 잘 되었소!
What is!?
뭐가!
If Osenchan calms down by this, we'll be dismissed and we'll be able to live restfully-dasu!
이걸로 오센짱이 진정하면 우리도 면직되고 느긋하게 살 수 있소!
Calm down? What are you talking about?
진정해? 뭔 소리냐.
I'm talking about a marriage-dasu. Osenchan and the Highness will marry-dasu.
결혼 말이오, 결혼. 오센짱하고 국왕이 결혼하오.
Marry!?
결혼!?
What's wrong, Kojirō?
왜 그래, 코지로?
S- Senhime marries?
세, 센히메 님이 결혼?
My, Kojirō, I didn't propose to the Highness yet! Right?
저런, 코지로도 참, 아직 국왕 전하께 프로포즈한 게 아니야. 그쵸?
Yes.
네.
Kojirō, you're always jumping to the conclusion too early!
코지로도 참 설레발친다니까!
My chest started to hurt...
갑자기 가슴이 아파졌다.
weeeeeeh! Stopstop!
에이이이이이! 멈춰멈춰!
Nope!
싫어!
Stop!
멈춰!
Stopstopstop!
멈춰멈춰멈춰!
I got you!
잡았소!
You're it-dasu, Otsuru!
자, 다음엔 오츠루가 술래이오!
Yes!
응!
Kojirō!
코지로!
Mr. Kojirō!
코지로 씨!
Kojirō! It's too early to sleep, even if you care about beauty and health-dasu!
코지로! 아무리 미용하고 건강에 조심한다고 해도, 아직 자기에는 너무 빠르오!
It's evening yet.
아직 해질녁이에요.
Musashi. Ms. Otsuru.
무사시. 오츠루 씨.
It seems that I'm sick.
나는 병에 걸린 것 같다.
S- sick? Sick of what-dasu?
벼, 병라니, 대체 무슨 병이오?
I don't know, but my chest hurts.
모르지만 가슴이 아프구나.
Your chest hurts?
가슴이 아파?
What a pretty sunset.
예쁜 노을이에요.
Yes.
그래.
To think that I'm with you at a place like this...
국왕 전하하고 둘이서 이러고 있다니...
Senhime's happy!
센히메, 기뻐!
Me too.
나도 그래.
I made a new poem!
오, 한 구절 생각났다!
Evening sunset dyes the sky over there in vermilion
저녁 노을로 하늘이 새빨갛게 물들었구나
That's the best among the ones you ever did!
와, 지금까지 한 것 중에서 최고에요!
Senhime, you should make one too.
센히메도 하나 만들어 봐.
Oh, okay, well...
아, 네, 어디...
I got one!
됐어요!
Evening sunset on the west sky promises clear tomorrow
서쪽 하늘에 저녁 노을 나오면 내일 맑으리
That's it.
이래요.
Don't you think that's too obvious?
음, 그건 너무 당연하지 않아요?
What's important about Haiku is, Senhime, impressing people with a hidden meaning inside words.
하이쿠라는 건, 센히메, 단어 속에 숨겨진 것이 감동시키는 것이에요.
You should study more.
더 공부해야겠네요.
Right.
네.
What? Mr. Kojirō is sick?
뭐라? 코지로 님이 중한 병에?
That's right-dasu. I never saw Kojirō like that-dasu.
그렇소. 코지로가 저런 걸 보는 건 처음이오.
It's just my thoughts, but Mr. Kojirō might die at this rate.
제 생각이지만, 이대로라면 코지로 씨, 죽을 지도 몰라요.
Since when he's like that?
언제부터 그 상태가 되었나요?
Let's see... when I said about Senhime's marriage...
어디, 오센짱 결혼 이야기를 막 했을 때일까...
Marriage?
결혼?
I see. I get it.
그렇군요. 그런 것이군요.
Mr. Jūbee! What's so funny-dasu? It's not a laughing matter-dasu!
주베 씨! 뭐가 이상하오! 웃을 일이 아니오!
Well, no, excuse me. Please be relieved. Mr. Kojirō's sickness isn't something that will put his life at stake.
아, 아니, 실례했습니다. 그래도 안심해 주세요. 코지로 님의 병은 목숨을 위협하는 정도의 것은 아닙니다.
Huh?
어?
It is lovesickness.
그건 사랑의 병입니다.
Lovesickness?
사랑의 병?
My chest hurts...
가슴이 아파...
How can this happen to me, the unrivaled Mister Kojirō...
천하의 미스터 코지로라는 자가...
Kojirō!
코지로!
Huh?
어라?
Oh, it's you, Musashi. Please be quiet.
무사시냐. 조용히 해 줘라.
What are you saying-dasu, Kojirō? I know-dasu!
뭔 소리이오, 코지로! 나, 알고 있소!
W- what are you talking about?
뭐, 뭔 소리냐.
Your sickness is something called lovesickness-dasu!
네 병은 사랑의 병이라는 놈이오!
L- lovesickness?
사, 사랑의 병?
Yeah-dasu! Your chest hurts because you did a discourtesy to Osenchan-dasu, Kojirō!
그렇소! 오센짱에게 실례해서 가슴이 아파오는 것이오, 코지로!
What are you blabbering about?
뭔 이상한 소릴 하고 있냐, 너는.
It's deplorable to stay in bed because you made a discourtesy, Kojirō, when you're looking to be the number one of Jipang!
지팡구 제일을 노리는 코지로가 실례 정도로 앓아눕다니, 부끄럽소!
Since we haven't settled this yet, I won't be able to stand this-dasu!
나하고의 승부도 안 났으니 죽으면 가만 안 있겠소!
Well, then, Musashi, we'll have a match. I'll show you who's stronger.
그래, 알겠다, 무사시. 결투다. 누가 강한지 네게 알려 주겠다.
I knew you would-dasu.
그래야 하오.
What? Kojirō?
어? 코지로가?
Yes. He couldn't tell it by himself, because he's too serious.
그래요. 그 분, 진지하다 못해 그걸 입으로 이야기를 못 했어요.
Kojirō... me?
코지로가, 나를?
Mr. Kojirō will die at this rate.
이대로는 코지로 씨가 죽고 말 거에요.
Only you can rescue Mr. Kojirō, Senhime!
코지로 씨를 구할 수 있는 건 센히메 님밖에 없어요!
The animal that cries caw caw must be a crow over there
까악까아악 울고 있는 동물은 까마귀일까
Alright. If he loves me to the extent he'll die, then I must respond to his devotion!
알겠어. 죽을 정도로 날 사랑해 준다면, 그 애정에 답해줘야만 해!
Grab your swords, Musashi!
자, 칼 들어라, 무사시!
I was waiting for this-dasu!
바라던 바오!
My chest...
가슴이...
Kojirō, we'll have a match after your lovesickness gets cured-dasu.
코지로, 네 사랑의 병이 낫고 나서 승부를 하오.
You're still saying that, Musashi? Don't even try to go easy on me.
또 그 소리냐, 무사시. 적당히 넘어갈 생각 마라.
Got it-dasu. You said it-dasu!
알겠소. 그렇게까지 말한다면!
Stop!
잠깐!
Stop it, you two!
둘 다 그만해!
S- Senhime!
세, 센히메 님!
Kojirō! No, Mr. Kojirō!
코지로! 아니, 코지로 씨!
Mr. Kojirō, I'm really sorry that I didn't realize you loved me, even when we were together for a whole year.
코지로 씨, 1년 내내 가까이 같이 있으면서, 당신이 저를 사랑해 주고 있다는 걸 알아채지 못했다니, 미안해요.
Senhime...
센히메 님...
Kojirō!
코지로!
E- er...
저, 저기...
E- excuse me, but I don't understand what's...
저, 저기, 무슨 말이신지 저는...
Huh? My chest doesn't hurt anymore.
어? 가슴 아픈 게 사라졌다.
Oh, it hurted because this fish spine stuck in my chest! Senhime helped me. Thank you.
뭐야, 물고기 가시가 가슴에 걸려서 아팠구나! 이야, 센히메 님 덕분입니다. 감사합니다.
What, fish spine?
뭐, 물고기 가시?
This is great! So great! Excellent!
이야, 잘됐어, 잘됐어, 잘됐어!
Oh, sure! It's really great!
아, 그래! 그거 참 잘 됐네!
I will not talk to you ever again!
너 따위하곤 살면서 다시는 말 안 할 거야!
What's going on?
대체 뭔 일이야?
What!? You're saying that I stayed in bed because I was rude to Senhime!?
뭐라고!? 내가 센히메 님께 실례해서 앓아누워!?
I am not a fragile man like that! Don't treat me like an idiot!
난 그런 나약한 사내가 아니다! 바보 취급 마라!
Musashi! Unforgivable! We'll have a duel!
무사시! 용서할 수 없다! 결투다!
Kojirō, I apologize-dasu!
코지로, 사과하고!
Musashi. Since when did you become so weak?
무사시. 너는 언제부터 그렇게 연약해졌냐.
What? Weak?
어? 연약?
Yes.
그렇다.
I am not insulting Ms. Otsuru.
나는 오츠루 씨 험담할 생각은 없다.
But, ever since Ms. Otsuru appeared, you became strange.
그러나 오츠루 씨가 나타난 이후로 넌 이상해졌다.
You're making out and saying "we'll marry-dasu!" all the time. Did you forget about becoming the number one of Jipang?
계속 농탕이나 치고, 결혼하오 라고 말이나 하고, 지팡구 제일이 되겠다는 네 목표는 잊었냐!
Remember the past. Remember the Musashi when he was rough, wild, and reckless!
옛날을 기억해내라. 거칠고 난폭하며 무모했던 때의 무사시를!
Do not follow her!
뒤쫒지 마라!
Alright. A duel.
그래, 결투.
I will accept-dasu!
받아 주겠소!
Good. We'll meet at Ganryu Island 6 in morning.
좋다. 내일 아침 6시, 간류 섬이다.
That bastard!
그 자식!
Your Highness!
국왕 전하!
(23th sentence of Ogura Hyakunin Isshu; translation taken from http://jti.lib.virginia.edu/japanese/hyakunin/index.html)
(오구라 백인일수의 23번째 문장)
As I view the moon Many things come into my mind And my thoughts are sad
달 보는 마음 여럿으로 복잡해 서글퍼진다
Yet it's not for me alone That the autumn time has come
가을이 나를 위해 온 것이 아니리니
Oh, Senhime!
오, 센히메!
Your Highness, I have a favor to ask.
국왕 전하, 부탁이 있습니다.
What is it?
뭔가요?
Please... please marry me!
저하고... 저하고 결혼해 주세요!
That's a good idea.
응, 그것도 괜찮은 생각이네요.
Let's do so.
그렇게 해요.
Thank you so much!
감사합니다!
I see.
그랬습니까.
Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō are having a duel...
무사시 님과 코지로 님이 결투를.
It's all my fault. If they fight each other, one of them will end up being hurt.
다 제 잘못이에요. 그래도, 이대로 둘이 싸운다면 무사시 씨하고 코지로 씨 중 하나는 상처를 입고 말 거에요.
That's why I'm asking you a favor, Mr. Jūbee. Please make them stop.
그러니까, 부탁드려요, 주베 씨. 그 들을 멈추어 주세요.
Ms. Otsuru.
오츠루 씨.
Yes?
네.
You have to understand them for now.
이건 이해해 주셔야 합니다.
What?
네?
We martial artists fight to improve oneselves.
저희 무예가는 싸우면서 자신을 단련하며 살아 갑니다.
Both Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō are not fighting to kill.
무사시 님도 코지로 님도 살생을 위해 싸우는 것이 아닙니다.
That is how we martial artists live.
그것이 무예가의 살아가는 방식입니다.
Please understand.
이해해 주십시오.
That's a lie!
그런 건 거짓말이야!
You're saying that's how martial artists live, but Mr. Jūbee and all others just love fighting!
무예가가 살아가는 방식이라 하지만, 주베 씨도 모두도 싸우는 게 좋을 뿐이야!
All men are barbaric!
남자는 다 야만스러워!
No! You idiot! You idiot! You idiot!
싫어! 바보바보바보!
Oh, well.
저런.
With various thoughts, the sun has risen, and Kojirō is waiting for Musashi eagerly at Ganryu Island.
여러 가지 생각을 담고 해는 떠올라, 간류 섬에서는 코지로가 지금 이제나저제나 하고 무사시를 기다리고 있었다.
Wait for the stormy latter half!
질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
He's late! What the hell is Musashi doing!?
늦어! 무사시 놈, 대체 뭘 하고 있는 거야!?
I think I promised something with somebody...
누군가하고 뭔가 약속했던 것 같은 기분이...
Right-dasu! I have a duel with Kojirō-dasu!
그렇소! 코지로하고 결투가 있소!
Wah! I'm late-dasu!
으악! 지각이오!
That Musashi bastard must have run away because he's so frightened! Hmph!
무사시 놈, 겁에 질려서 달아난 게 틀림없어. 흥! 애초에 그게 다인 남자 놈이였냐. 다시 봤다!
Er, no, correction; I overlooked him!
아, 아니, 다시, 잘못 봤다!
Mr. Samurai! Why are you going to Ganryu Island?
사무라이 씨! 간류 섬엔 왜 가시나?
To have a duel-dasu!
결투이오!
Without a sword?
칼도 없이?
Wah! I forgot-dasu!
으악! 잊고 왔소!
What are you doing, Musashi!? You're completely late!
뭘 하고 있냐, 무사시! 완전히 지각이다!
I'm sorry-dasu!
미안하오!
Let's do this, Musashi!
해 보자, 무사시!
Right-dasu!
좋소!
Musashi, are you trying to be funny with that sword?
무사시, 그 칼은 뭔 장난이냐?
Hmph-dasu! My Tenkūmaru is too valuable to use it to you, Kojirō-dasu!
흥이오! 코지로를 상대로 천공환을 쓰는 건 아깝소!
That will be your last futile retort!
억지도 그게 최후다!
Ganryu! Tsubamegaeshi!
간류! 츠바메가에시!
I'll finish you!
끝장이다!
How stubborn...
끈질긴 놈...
H- hey, Osenchan!
어, 어라, 오센짱!
What!?
뭐라고!?
It was a lie-dasu!
거짓말이오!
Musashi! Why are you so deliberately malicious?
무사시! 넌 왜 그렇게 심술궂냐?
A lie is also a pee-dasu!
거짓말도 소변이오.
(shōben: urine, hōben: means)
그 소리를 지껄일 거라면 거짓말도 방편이다!
They are similar-dasu!
비슷한 것이오!
Really, you're one guy that never thinks!
정말, 아무것도 생각 안 하는 놈이군!
I do think for a bit-dasu!
조금은 생각하오!
Tell me what you're thinking about!
뭘 생각하고 있는지 말해 봐라!
For example, morning meals...
예를 들어, 아침밥이라던가...
And?
그리고!
Lunch...
점심밥이라던가...
Dinner...
저녁밥이라던가...
Do you ever think about something that isn't about food!?
네 머리에는 먹을 것밖에 없냐!
I think about Otsuru too-dasu!
오츠루도 생각하오.
I wonder what's Otsuru doing by now-dasu...
오츠루, 지금쯤 뭘 하고 있을까...
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Now that I'm thinking about Otsuru, it's like I'm hearing her-dasu!
아, 오츠루 생각하니, 나, 왠지 들리는 것 같소.
Mr. Musashi! I brought your swords!
무사시 씨! 칼 가지고 왔어!
Otsuru!
오츠루!
Mr. Musashi, I apologize about what happened yesterday.
무사시 씨, 어제는 미안했어.
It's alright-dasu. It's not Otsuru's fault-dasu. Blame Kojirō-dasu.
괜찮소. 이건 오츠루가 잘못한 게 아니오. 코지로가 나빴소.
I won't bother you, Mr. Musashi, so, please fight all you can.
나, 무사시 씨 방해되지 않도록 할 테니까 힘껏 싸워.
Got it-dasu. I'll wreck Kojirō, for harassing you, Otsuru-dasu!
알겠소. 오츠루도 괴롭힌 코지로를 엉망으로 만들어 주겠소!
Your blabbering ends now. Let's finish this, Musashi.
지껄임도 거기까지다. 해 보자, 무사시.
Sure-dasu!
좋소!
Just a moment.
잠깐만.
Giving up?
항복이냐?
Pee time-dasu.
오줌 타임이오.
Otsuru, look the other side for a moment-dasu!
오츠루, 잠깐 저기 보시오!
Alright.
응.
Tch. Maybe I'll do that too.
쳇, 이 틈에 나도 해 둘까.
I want those two to stop by now...
둘 다, 이제 그만했으면 좋겠는데.
Let's do this, Musashi!
가자, 무사시!
Right-dasu!
좋소!
I'll become your wife when I grow up, Mr. Musashi!
나, 자라면 무사시 씨 아내가 될 거야!
That's why you have to become a strong samurai!
그러니까, 강한 사무라이가 되어 줘!
Got it-dasu! I'll become the number one martial artist of Jipang-dasu!
알겠소! 나, 지팡구 제일의 무예가가 되겠소!
Mr. Musashi...
무사시 씨...
Musashi! Kojirō!
무사시! 코지로!
-Everyone! -Everyone! What's up-dasu?
-다들! -다들! 무슨 일이오!
We heard about your duel from Mr. Jūbee, so we hurried our way to here.
주베 씨한테 결투 이야기 듣고 서둘러 왔어.
I see-dasu!
그렇소!
It seems that the match isn't over yet.
아직 결판은 안 난 모양이군요.
Yeah, it's great that we weren't late!
그래, 안 늦어서 다행이다!
We'll be witnesses, so please fight, and don't mind us!
우리가 입회할 테니까 신경쓰지 말고 싸워 주셔!
Thank you-dasu. I'll finish up Kojirō right away-dasu!
고맙소. 코지로 따위는 곧장 해치워 주겠소!
That's my line!
그건 내가 할 말이다!
Oh, they aren't here to stop them.
뭐야, 다들 멈추게 하려 온 게 아니네.
How disappointing.
실망이야.
Let's do this, Musashi!
가자, 무사시!
Come whenever you're ready-dasu!
언제라도 환영이오!
Secret Sword Tsubamegaeshi!
비검 츠바메가에시!
I can see you-dasu!
다 보이오!
What!?
뭣이!?
I can see your next move, probably because I kept fighting with you all along-dasu!
코지로하고 계속 싸워 왔던 덕분인지 다음 동작이 보이오!
Hmph. Musashi, you grew up.
흥, 무사시, 성장했구나.
You were nothing more than a brat when we first met, but it seems that you came closer to me by now.
처음 만났을 때는 그냥 얘새끼였더니, 지금은 내게 다가온 듯 하구나.
Hmph-dasu! I grew up more than you, Kojirō-dasu!
흥이오! 내 쪽이 코지로보다 성장했소!
And how is that!?
어딜 봐서!
I have love-dasu!
내게는 사랑이 있소!
Love!?
사랑!?
I have the objective of love, of marrying Otsuru after becoming the number one of Jipang-dasu!
내게는 지팡구 제일이 되어서 오츠루하고 결혼하겠다는 사랑의 목표가 있소!
Kojirō! Do you have an objective-dasu?
코지로! 네게는 목표 있소?
My, Mr. Musashi, you're embarrassing me!
저런, 무사시 씨도 참, 부끄럽게.
My objective?
내 목표?
Senhime?
센히메?
Y- yes?
네, 네!
What were you thinking?
뭘 생각하고 있었어?
W- well, that's...
아, 아니, 그게...
I know.
나는 알아.
What?
예?
I envy those birds.
새는 좋겠지.
They can fly freely.
자유롭게 하늘을 날 수 있지.
They must be finding for something, at the other of the sky.
분명 하늘의 저편에서 찾는 무언가가 있겠지.
Senhime, you're like a bird.
센히메도 새같아.
Yes?
예?
Your wings must be itching to fly on the wide open sky, from a while ago.
아까부터 넓은 하늘을 날고 싶다고, 날개가 근질근질하고 있겠지.
I don't have wings.
날개는 제게는 없어요.
I am a tree. A tree that rooted deeply to the ground.
나는 나무야. 대지에 단단히 뿌리내린 나무야.
I cannot fly.
날아갈 수 없어.
Senhime. You should fly on the wide open sky.
센히메. 넓은 하늘을 날아.
Find whatever you wanted, and when you're tired, come back to me, and rest on my branch.
무언가를 찾다가도, 힘들면 돌아와서 내 가지에서 날개를 쉬어.
Your Highnes...
국왕 전하...
I'm sorry!
죄송합니다!
What did you do?
뭘 하신 것입니까.
I was rude.
실례했다.
Hm?
예?
C- chink in the armor...
비, 빈틈이다...
What's this?
뭡니까?
We have a problem, everyone! Edotopia is being attacked by a large number of ninjas!
큰일이야, 다들! 에도토피가 다수의 닌자에게 공격당하고 있어!
A- are you serious!? That's a big problem!
저, 정말입니까? 그건 큰일이네요!
Hanzō wasn't dead yet. Hanzō is attacking Edotopia!
한조는 아직 죽지 않았던 거야. 한조가 에도토피아를 공격하고 있어!
-What-dasu? -Hanzō!?
-뭣이오!? -한조가!?
Everyone, get onto Chokuden! Let's go to Edotopia!
다들 초공전에 타! 에도토피아에 가자!
To know that Hanzō's still alive, he's really persistent!
아직 살아 있었다니, 한조도 참 끈질긴 놈이구나!
Oh, that's a lie.
예, 그건 거짓말입니다.
Senhime made up this lie to stop Mr. Musashi and Mr. Kojirō from fighting.
무사시 님과 코지로 님의 결투를 멈추기 위해 센히메 님이 생각해 내신 거짓말입니다.
A lie, eh?
거짓말이야?
You surprised us...
철렁했네...
Musashi, we'll finish this later.
무사시, 승부는 나중이다.
Right-dasu.
그렇소.
I'll make an objective of my own.
나도 무언가 목표를 세우도록 하지.
That's great-dasu. We'll have a match again after that-dasu.
그건 잘 됐소. 그 때 다시 승부이오.
OK.
OK.
Flying feels good!
하늘을 난다는 건 기분 좋네.
Yes. It's just like as if we became birds.
네. 마치 새가 된 것 같아요.
More than rivals, Musashi and Kojirō are tied together with friendship. Their flowery road will continued to the future.
호적수를 넘어 우정으로 맺어진 무사시와 코지로. 사내의 꽃길은 미래로 이어진다.
But, it might be the love, what wins at last.
그러나, 마지막에 이기는 것은 사랑일 지도 모른다.
Until you catch the day of love, do not be discouraged advance! That is the road of Musashi: Musashi Road.
영원한 사랑의 날을 잡을 때까지, 꺾이지 말고 나아가라! 그것이 무사시의 길, 무사시 로드이다.
I fought and I got beaten
싸우고 맞았어
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
I can't lose, so take my blow!
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Next is delightful lunchtime
다음 시간 즐거운
But it's not delightful today
급식일 텐데
The thunder of my teacher
선생님의 벼락이
only hit me and nobody else
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
I tried to explain
사정을 말해도
But he won't listen
들어주지 않는 채
Now whatever I do
어떻게 해도 역시
I end up crying
눈물이 나오고 말아
Don't cry when you eat, or
울면서 밥먹으면
it tastes totally bad
완전 맛없어
you'll feel downhearted
왠지 안타까워